<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Professional Portfolio on ANTONIO VAZQUEZ BRUST</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Professional Portfolio on ANTONIO VAZQUEZ BRUST</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title> Course: Data Science and Public Policy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/course-data-science-and-public-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/course-data-science-and-public-policy/</guid>
      <description>Hired by the Buenos Aires City Government, I designed the Data Science and Public Policy to address the growing need for governments to develop new capabilities in their employees. The goal was to provide teams from different government areas with data analysis skill to enable evidence-based decision-making.&#xA;Topics: Big Data and the City. Definitions, case analysis, future. New data sources, new roles in urban planning. Introduction to R, the environment for analyzing, modeling, visualizing, and communicating with data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Index of Confidence and Access to Vaccines (ICAV)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/index-of-confidence-and-access-to-vaccines-icav/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/index-of-confidence-and-access-to-vaccines-icav/</guid>
      <description>As a Research Fellow at the Bunge and Born Foundation, I helped develop the Index of Confidence and Access to Vaccines (ICAV). The index was designed to identify barriers that hinder access to vaccination, as well as changes in public confidence regarding the importance, safety, and efficacy of vaccines.&#xA;Since 2019, the Bunge and Born Foundation has been conducting the ICAV, a project to study and measure the causes of the wide gap between the optimal level of vaccination and the rates achieved in Argentina.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Training for Public Servants</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/data-science-training-for-public-servants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/data-science-training-for-public-servants/</guid>
      <description>In 2019 I designed a training program based on the requirements of the Capacity Development for Innovation Directorate of the Ministry of Modernization of Argentina.&#xA;The training consisted of three practice-focused seminars. An introductory one on data science, which taught programming principles and analytics using R, the language for data analysis and visualization. Building on the knowledge acquired in the initial course, two specialization seminars allowed for a deeper understanding in key areas: one focused on statistical analysis and machine learning, and the other on spatial information analysis and visualization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Fair Housing with Geospatial Data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/supporting-fair-housing-with-geospatial-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/supporting-fair-housing-with-geospatial-data/</guid>
      <description>I collaborated as a data scientist with The American City Coalition, an NGO in Boston that develops strategies for revitalizing neighborhoods where vulnerable populations reside.&#xA;I was responsible for the large-scale collection and analysis of geospatial and demographic data to assess the effectiveness of policies aimed at racial desegregation based on access to public housing in the state of Massachusetts, USA.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
