<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Professional Portfolio on ANTONIO VAZQUEZ BRUST</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Professional Portfolio on ANTONIO VAZQUEZ BRUST</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MAIIA: Mapping of Informal Settlements based on Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/maiia-mapping-of-informal-settlements-based-on-artificial-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/maiia-mapping-of-informal-settlements-based-on-artificial-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>MAIIA is an algorithm that enables automated mapping of informal urban settlements through the analysis of satellite images. To facilitate its implementation, it is distributed as a pre-configured operating system image (via Docker) and alternatively as a set of Python notebooks, providing scripts that can train a detection model and apply it to new images in just two steps.&#xA;I led the development of the MAIIA algorithms thanks to the support of the Housing and Urban Development Division of the Inter-American Development Bank.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UrbanPy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/urbanpy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/urbanpy/</guid>
      <description>UrbanPy is an open-source Python library that automates the entire workflow required to obtain geographic boundaries of a city, estimate its population, locate places of interest, and even calculate travel times through the local street network.&#xA;UrbanPy is particularly useful for estimating accessibility indices—i.e., where people live farthest away from key resources and services such as schools, hospitals, bus stops, places to buy food, and so on.&#xA;I prototyped the library and led its development, thanks to the support of the Inter-American Development Bank.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Launching the Postgraduate Course in Big Data and Territorial Intelligence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/launching-the-postgraduate-course-in-big-data-and-territorial-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/launching-the-postgraduate-course-in-big-data-and-territorial-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>The postgraduate course in Big Data and Territorial Intelligence at the Latin American Faculty of Social Sciences (FLACSO) teaches principles of computational statistics, programming, and Geographic Information Systems (GIS) alongside the theoretical framework for their application in territorial management.&#xA;I designed the curriculum for the course and acted as its academic coordinator, plus professor in Geographic Data Science, for its first three years.&#xA;The curse, still offered, teaches students how to use spatial analysis and data science to tackle complex geography-related problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Data and Neglected Diseases</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/big-data-and-neglected-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/big-data-and-neglected-diseases/</guid>
      <description>This interdisciplinary project combined the analysis of billions of anonymized mobile phone call records with epidemiological, sociodemographic, and healthcare databases. This allowed us to accurately identify areas characterized by high contact of their inhabitants with areas where the Chagas disease is endemic, and which also record a high level of socioeconomic and healthcare vulnerability.&#xA;The key to the results is that they allow for the identification of urban or rural areas where it is a priority to take healthcare actions and, as they are outside the endemic zone of the disease, they may not be considered as focal points of attention.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmental Conservation Fund Award - Urban Green Space Atlas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/environmental-conservation-fund-award-urban-green-space-atlas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/environmental-conservation-fund-award-urban-green-space-atlas/</guid>
      <description>The Environmental Conservation Fund aims to incentivize research and management projects that seek environmental conservation and sustainable development in the country. In 2019, I received the award in the Urban Environments category for my project Urban Green Space Atlas for Argentine Cities&#xA;There is growing evidence that urban green spaces act as reducers of inequality. Health benefits associated with access have a greater effect among socioeconomically vulnerable populations.&#xA;In Argentina, improving access and evaluating the effects of public green spaces is challenging, particularly on a federal scale, due to a lack of official and comprehensive information regarding the quality, location, and extent of urban green areas.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Course: Data Science and Public Policy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/course-data-science-and-public-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/course-data-science-and-public-policy/</guid>
      <description>Hired by the Buenos Aires City Government, I designed the Data Science and Public Policy to address the growing need for governments to develop new capabilities in their employees. The goal was to provide teams from different government areas with data analysis skill to enable evidence-based decision-making.&#xA;Topics: Big Data and the City. Definitions, case analysis, future. New data sources, new roles in urban planning. Introduction to R, the environment for analyzing, modeling, visualizing, and communicating with data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Index of Confidence and Access to Vaccines (ICAV)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/index-of-confidence-and-access-to-vaccines-icav/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/index-of-confidence-and-access-to-vaccines-icav/</guid>
      <description>As a Research Fellow at the Bunge and Born Foundation, I helped develop the Index of Confidence and Access to Vaccines (ICAV). The index was designed to identify barriers that hinder access to vaccination, as well as changes in public confidence regarding the importance, safety, and efficacy of vaccines.&#xA;Since 2019, the Bunge and Born Foundation has been conducting the ICAV, a project to study and measure the causes of the wide gap between the optimal level of vaccination and the rates achieved in Argentina.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The GPE (Georeferenced Program Evaluation) R package</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/the-gpe-georeferenced-program-evaluation-r-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/the-gpe-georeferenced-program-evaluation-r-package/</guid>
      <description>GPE (short for &amp;ldquo;Geo-referenced Program Evaluation&amp;rdquo;) is a package of functions for the R programming language. It was designed to make life easier for those analyzing movement dynamics in urban contexts.&#xA;For example, to measure the impact of social programs where access metrics (distances and travel times, places visited, etc.) are of interest. I originally developed the set of functions that now make up GPE to assist the Inter-American Development Bank (IDB) and the Buenos Aires City Government in evaluating the City&amp;rsquo;s Cultural Pass Program, an initiative to encourage access to cultural offerings (music, film, literature, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Training for Public Servants</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/data-science-training-for-public-servants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/data-science-training-for-public-servants/</guid>
      <description>In 2019 I designed a training program based on the requirements of the Capacity Development for Innovation Directorate of the Ministry of Modernization of Argentina.&#xA;The training consisted of three practice-focused seminars. An introductory one on data science, which taught programming principles and analytics using R, the language for data analysis and visualization. Building on the knowledge acquired in the initial course, two specialization seminars allowed for a deeper understanding in key areas: one focused on statistical analysis and machine learning, and the other on spatial information analysis and visualization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Fair Housing with Geospatial Data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/project/supporting-fair-housing-with-geospatial-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/project/supporting-fair-housing-with-geospatial-data/</guid>
      <description>I collaborated as a data scientist with The American City Coalition, an NGO in Boston that develops strategies for revitalizing neighborhoods where vulnerable populations reside.&#xA;I was responsible for the large-scale collection and analysis of geospatial and demographic data to assess the effectiveness of policies aimed at racial desegregation based on access to public housing in the state of Massachusetts, USA.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
